# **Dane Janssen**

Full Stack Web Developer St Petersburg, FL | (321)297-8973

Portfolio | GitHub | LinkedIn | Email

Driven web developer with the ability to pick up new languages and technologies as needed. Prior to being a web developer, I worked as a Regional Sales Manager and Team Leader in the renewable energy industry converting businesses and homes from fossil fuels to renewable energies and solar arrays

## **Software Development Skills**

• Debugging, JavaScript, Python, Node.js, React, Express, Redux, RESTful API, PostgreSQL, Sequelize, Bootstrap, Flexbox, AWS, HTML, CSS, Git, Github

#### **Education**

Digital Crafts | Certificate in Software Engineering | Houston, TX

Sept 2021 – Jan 2022

 Software engineering training program covering full-stack development including, but not limited to JavaScript, Python, including an emphasis on cutting-edge frameworks like React/Redux and server-side technologies including Node.js, Express, and PostgreSQL.

Valencia College | A.A. in Computer Science | Orlando, FL

May 2017 - Present

CPC Certification, AAPC | Remote

Jan 2012- Apr 2012

CPB Certification, AAPC | Remote

Jan 2012- Apr 2012

HIPPA Certification, Bridgefront

Sept 2009 - Dec 2009

# **Web Development Portfolio**

Boss Developers Pizza | https://BossDevPizza.netlify.app/ | https://github.com/NewDev11/BDPizza.git

**April 2021** 

- Member of a 3-person development team building a dynamic restaurant website.
- User can enter a username and password and place to go orders and save their info for future orders
- Primary responsibilities included linking backend routes, styling and calling info from database as well as storing data via local host to dynamically populate cart items and order totals.
- Built with HTML, JavaScript, node.is, CSS, Sequelize, Flexbox, and Bootstrap.

Travel App | TavelApp hyperlink | github.com/DaneJanssen/TravelApp

March 2022

- Member of a 4-person development team building a travel app website that allows users to search for fun events happening in real time within the users chosen city.
- User experience allows users to search for a specific city and will be shown dynamic results pulled from the web.
- Primary responsibilities included learning to use API calls to fetch data from event sites, storing user data in local storage and minor styling
- Built with HTML, JavaScript, node.js, CSS, Sequelize, Flexbox, and Bootstrap.

Virtual Casino | https://virtualcasino.netlify.app/ | https://github.com/NewDev11/Virtual-Casino.git

Feb 2022

- Created a single player online card game.
- User has the ability to play blackjack against a virtual opponent online.
- Primary responsibilities included implementation of game and card logic as well as minor styling.
- Built with HTML, JavaScript, node.js, CSS, Sequelize, Flexbox, and Bootstrap.

## **Professional Work Experience**

Solar Bear | Regional Sales Manager | Tampa, FL Blue Sky Solar Energy | Sales Manager | Orlando, FL Yale Clinic | Operations Director | Orlando, FL Lajoie Medical Group | Operations Director | Orlando, FL Jan 2019 – Present April 2017 – Jan 2019 Feb 2015 – April 2017 Sept 2009 – Feb 2015